<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A new parliament, or representative for the perpetual peace and  quiet of this nation, and of other parts (which be or shall be incorporated with the same) in the enjoyment of their just rights and liberties, as in the most peaceable times of old they have been : now proposed to be chosen and held certainly in all future times ... : with other things in order to the prevention of unlawful exacting from the people of this nation, every year hereafter, millions of money formerly so exacted / written by W.L.</title>
            <author>Leach, William.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 41KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49861</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">27300837</idno>
  <idno type="VID">110069</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240892978</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L775A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R43365</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">27300837</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49861)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 110069)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1724:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A new parliament, or representative for the perpetual peace and  quiet of this nation, and of other parts (which be or shall be incorporated with the same) in the enjoyment of their just rights and liberties, as in the most peaceable times of old they have been : now proposed to be chosen and held certainly in all future times ... : with other things in order to the prevention of unlawful exacting from the people of this nation, every year hereafter, millions of money formerly so exacted / written by W.L.</title>
                  <author>Leach, William.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the Year, Anno Dom. 1651.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Attributed by Wing to William Leach.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Great Britain. --  Parliament --  Elections.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Zev Berger </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Zev Berger</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:110069:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:110069:1"/>
            <p>A NEW PARLIAMENT, OR REPRESENTATIVE FOR The perpetual Peace and quiet of this Nation, and of other parts, (which be or shall be incorporated with the same) in the enjoyment of their just Rights and Liberties, AS In the most peaceable times of old they have been; Now proposed to be chosen and held certain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in all future times of a necessity, and a Method or Form for the choosing thereof; without charge or trouble to those to be elected, and little to them to elect, in all times hereafter. WITH Other things in order to the prevention of unlawful ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acting from the People of this Nation, every year hereafter, Millions of <hi>Money</hi> formerly so exacted</p>
            <p>Written by W. L.</p>
            <p>LONDON, <hi>Printed in the Year, Anno Dom.</hi> 1651:</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:110069:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:110069:2"/>
            <head>A new Parliament, or Representative, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N the times when Parliaments were frequent, being anciently ordained to be once every year, or oftner, as occasions in those times happn'ed: the people of this Nation were ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pert and careful of their choice, knowing what would follow to their ruine, if such Parliaments should not be just and careful in their consultations and actings for the publick good: And then they only chose those, whom in their experiences and judgements, they knew to be, or had certain intelligence of, were honest, just, learned, careful, and discreet; and knowing or capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of the knowledge of such imployment, and most like so to be qualified in the residue, as appeared by their suddain dispatch of business (which came before them) and by their adjournments, or prorogations of such Parliaments, after a quarter of a years time, or lesse sitting, which is a sign that our Ancestors have forborn, and declined the choice of younglings and novices, and others (who have not understood that which they ought to have done) according to their trust and duty in such imployment, for their own and Countries weale, (for whom they have been, and then were chosen and elected) and no man can imagine any other; but that most of those Members of <hi>Parliament</hi> (for such Members of <hi>Parliament</hi> in the then future times) were chosen and elected, willingly and deservedly, during their lives and continuance in their perfect healths and memories, in all <hi>Parliaments</hi> (which then followed) in respect of their honesty, long experience and judgement: of which desert it is hoped there be divers now. And then were many Lords or Peers of this Nation very learned and judicious in the Common &amp; other Laws of the same; &amp; they with others endeavoured to see that full &amp; speedy justice were done.
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:110069:3"/> And when the <hi>Parliaments</hi> were so often held, the Lawes of this Nation were accounted (and deservedly) the best, most speedy, and cheap in all Christendom, the same being grounded upon Customs and Statutes, the first from time to time agreeing to the Law of God, and upholding the Christian people in maintenance of the Christian Religion from time to time, and their quiet and peaceable living in the exercise of the same, according to the light which our Auncestors had in former times, and if any have been thereunto dissenting, and so found upon debate after solemn ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gument, they have been adjudged or considered of to be bad, and for that cause not to be admitted but abolished, and so have been from time to time in those dayes, (though of long time unquesti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned before) and the latter have been altered or repealed when apparent inconveniences have been found thereby; In which e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>steeme and account it is hoped the Law will be again when exacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons crept in without Authority (which hath brought an <hi>Odium</hi> upon the Law and Lawyers, and caused an endeavour or desire in some to debar them from being Members of the <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament</hi>) be removed; for without such Lawyers as be most honest, learned, and judicious in those Lawes (being grounded upon the quintessence of right reason, fully debated upon by ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nest and learned Lawyers, and maturely deliberated upon, and considered of, by many honest, learned and judicious Justiciars of this Nation, for many hundreds of years) it is feared that there can be expected very few good Lawes or Ordinances for this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, but a danger of a confusion without the assistance of such, being none other of any other profession have been heard of to attain to such learning and judgement, without long and hard study, and great expence and trouble, and the study thereof hath been so difficult, that it hath been accounted the most trouble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>some in this Nation, and few (who have long studied in that profession) have come to any considerable perfection, learning, judgement or understanding in the same, though many other in other Arts, Sciences, or Professions, who have therein not studi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed half so long in the same (although but of mean capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cities) have attained to considerable learning, judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and understanding in the same; and few or none of such exactions were so introduced or continued by the meanes of any
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:110069:3"/> Lawyer accounted honest, learned, and judicious; but if any de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sire to know by whom? upon inquiry, they may find it out with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out much difficulty.</p>
            <p>And whereas great men bearing sway in Counties, Cities, and other Corporations in latter times, most commonly have stood and endeavoured either to be Members of the <hi>Parliament</hi> them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, or otherwise have sided for some of their acquaintance, and used all the endeavour they could to procure or prefer them into, and for such imployment, principally for their cred t or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute; both these and those being of mean judgements and learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in any thing, and some of them in the first place seeking their own ends, (as many have feared and doubted) by reason where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of divers such qualified persons have obtained such imployment; which (as is much doubted by divers) hath obstructed or retarded the speedy dispatch and settlement of the publick business of this Nation, some in respect of their own self-ends, and others through their neglect, carelesness or ignorance. And many of such have so prevailed with their Tenants, Allies, Debtors and others, (up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on whom by feasting, filling them with strong drink, imploying them in hunting, hawking, and other imployments of profit and pleasure,) they have gained such influence, that they have cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed many of such persons being simple, to be for the election of any (who have provided most liberal for their feasting and carow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing) whatsoever hath or was like to become of the main business after, for their own (if they would or could have understood or or regarded it) and others of the people of this Nation, benefit and advantage.</p>
            <p>And whereas since the long intermission of Parliaments, many Members thereof have been far to seek, to know how to perform their duties in such trust; which hath brought divers of the Nobi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity and other great men of this Nation, (or so esteemed) to fall in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to such carelesness and neglect of learning, the knowledge and judgement in and of the Lawes, that they have not understood their own and the common good, as some of them have run and hurried into and upon excess and ryot, whereby they have de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>servedly fallen and come to ruine. And since those times they have been as long, or ten times more in understanding their du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties and power which they had to do, as Members of <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:110069:4"/> as formerly such Members before such intermissions have been, to finish that which was to be done in the <hi>Parliaments</hi> in their times.</p>
            <p>And whereas lately divers differences have been about the choice and election of Knights and Burgesses for the high Court of <hi>Parliament,</hi> and divers Knights and Gentlemen have been put to great excessive charges about the same, more then in former times hath been used, and great ambiguity hath been about due elections, what persons of right ought to elect, and be elected into such trust.</p>
            <p>For prevention whereof, and remedy in this behalf; and to the end and intent, that all Knights or Burgesses, who shall at any time hereafter elect or be elected for this high Assembly, may be chosen by the affection of the people respectively, and by those only who have or shall have lawful and undoubted power and Authority so to elect, or be elected; and not for fear of any, or for, or in respect of any lucre of any thing, and without charge to any one so to be elected, and very little trouble or charge to them who shall have power so to elect or choose.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Written by</hi> William Leach <hi>at</hi> Felmersham, <hi>a little after the writs of Summons last went out, in the late Kings time for summoning a Parliament; in part, and other part thereof, immediately after the Act made for the Triennial Parliaments, and the residue thereof since: proposed and tendered now to the consideration of all the people of this Nation; to the intent, that any who please, should write against the same, or any part thereof, or for amendment or support of it, or any part of the same in convenient time, and that those (who shall approve of the same) may petition to have the same taken into speedy consideration or,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Be enacted,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That immediately after any Writ for election, or other Command or Authority shall lawfully issue or go out, or be given to the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of any of the Counties, Cities, Boroughs, Cinque-Ports, or Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porations, or other places of this Nation, or of any other place (which have incorporated, or shall incorporate with the same) for electing or chu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ng of Knights, Burgesses, Barons, or o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>her Members of, or for such Counties, Cities, Boroughs, Cinque-Ports, or Corporations; or other such several places before mentioned; the Inhabitants of every
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:110069:4"/> Hundred, Lathor Wapentake, or other Divisions thereof, shall be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powered and authorized to, and may make their choice and election in that behalf. And that every such Inhabitant, or as many as will, (who hath or shall have a voice for the choice of their Representers, or the Members of future Parliaments of this Nation, or of such parts as be or shall be incorporated with them) to have Power and Authority, and may deliver in; to the chief Constable, or other chief Officer of such Hundred, or other Division a Note or Notes written in Parchment or Paper of one or two names of such as every of them do or shall elect or choose for such Member or Members, Represen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter or Representers to be of or for such Parliament, or Representative, written or printed in this manner following, if he or they do or shall e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect two.</hi>
            </p>
            <figure>
               <p>Sir <hi>John A</hi> of <hi>M.</hi> in the County of <hi>N.</hi> Knight, or Esquire, or <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as he be, or shall be of Dignity, or Quality.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thomas B.</hi> of <hi>C.</hi> Esquire, Gentleman, Merchant, or <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as he be, or shall be of Quality, or Profession.</p>
            </figure>
            <p>Cut between the two middle lines, but not quite parted, and may double such Note or Notes together, the one name upon the other, so that such Names may not be read until such Note or Notes be, or shall be opened, and deliver the same to such chief Constable or other Officer in a paper close sealed with the Name or Names of him o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> them upon the same, (who do or shall so in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>close such Note or Notes.) And that such chief Constable shall deliver all such Notes (which shall be so delivered unto him) to the Shrieffe or his Deputy of such County within 14. dayes next after, a competent number of the same or some from the greater part of the Towns or Villages within his Hundred, be or shall be so delivered unto him at the Market-Town within such Hundred
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:110069:5"/> or thereunto next adjoyning (where such Sheriff shall be impow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ered and compelled to keep a <hi>Box</hi> with a little hole in the top thereof, made in the form or the fashion of a Box to put money into) and that such Box shall be locked and sealed up close by such Sheriff and 4 or 5 Knights, Esquires, or Gentlemen of such County (who shall and will be ayding and assisting to such Sheriff in that behalf, and first offer to attend that duty, or in default thereof by the same number of such as such Sheriff shall call to his assistance in that behalf,) and that within one Moneth next after such Parliament or Representative shall be to meet (then and not before) such <hi>Box</hi> shall be opened, and such Notes taken out and viewed, and that every one of the same which shall have 2 names written upon the same, shall be cut or torn in sunder; and that every part of such Note, and every such other Note which shall have only one single Name written on the same; for one there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon as a Member or Representer so chosen or elected▪ shall be sorted and filed on a string together; and that such Knight, Es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>squire or Gentleman [whose Name shall be written in most such Notes] shall be the first Knight for the Inhabitants for such Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty or Shire, and that such other, whose Name shall be written in most of such Notes next, may be the second Knight or Represen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for the Inhabitants of such Shire or County; and in and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the same manner, concerning 3. 4. 5. 6. or more, which shall be named or written for great Counties, and may sit and act as Members in and of such Parliament or Representative, and that every such Member may have, receive, and recover the usual al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowances of and from such Counties, or the Inhabitants, as usu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally have been allowed or paid, to one of the Members of former Parliaments for such County, and have the same remedy for the same.</p>
            <p>And that the like Notes may be delivered into the Major or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther head-Officer, or Officers of every of such Cities, Boroughs, Cinque-ports, or Corporations, or of the several other places be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore mentioned, or Counties of the same, of or, for, or concerning Burgesses, Barons, or other Members or Representers of or for such Cities or other places in the same manner and form be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore mentioned, as such former Notes are to be delivered to such chief Constable.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:110069:5"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:110069:6"/>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:110069:6"/>
            <p>And that such Major, or such other Officer or Officers of the said Cities or places with them mentioned, may keep a Box of the form, fashion or Model before mentioned. And that the same shall be sealed or locked up close by such Major or other last mentioned Officer, and 4. or 5. or more for every great City, as <hi>London, Norwich, Bristol, York,</hi> and such like (which shall be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der 20. in number of the most eminent, ancient, discreet, and able Aldermen, or Burgesses, or other Seniors, or Ancients of such Cities, Boroughs, or other places before mentioned, with the same, who shall and will be aiding and assisting to such Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jors, or other Officers before with them mentioned in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, and first tender his or their aid or assistance therein, or in default thereof by the same number of the like qualified persons, as such Majors or others with them mentioned, shall require to assist him therein. And that within three weeks next before such Parliament or Representative shall be to begin (then and not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore) such Box shall be opened, and such Notes taken out and viewed; and that every of the same which shall have 2. names written on the same, shall be cut or torn in two peeces; and that every such Note, &amp; every such other Note which shall have only one single name thereupon written for one as aforesaid, shall be sorted and filed in manner and form before mentioned. And that such Knight, Esquire, Gentleman, Merchant, or other person, as before to be mentioned in such Note (whose name shall happen to be writ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>en in most of such Notes) shall be one of the <hi>Burgesses, Barons,</hi> or Members, or Representers for the Inhabitants or such City, or other of the places therewith before mentioned; and that such other whose name shall be written in most of such Notes next, shall be another of such Burgesses, Barons, or Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers or Representers; and that all of them may vote, sit, and act as before is mentioned, and in the same manner before mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, for and concerning such City, which is to have more then two such Members, and that every of such Members or Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>senters may have, receive, and recover the usual allowances, of and from such Cities, Boroughs, and other places before there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with mentioned, of the Inhabitants thereof, as usual have been pay'd or allowed to one of the Members of former Parliaments, for such respective City, Borough, or other place before mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and have the same remedy for the same.</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:110069:7"/>
            <p>And that the most honest, learned, discreet and wise, as shall be of any such respective Counties, Cities, or other places before mentioned, as anciently have been for the same, only may be so chosen and elected Members or Representers.</p>
            <p>And that every Parliament or Representative which shall be next chosen [in like manner as hath been in ancient times] may continue only for a year from the first beginning thereof, and then dissolve of course.</p>
            <p>And that such Members of or for new Parliaments or Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sentatives may be so chosen by such Inhabitants, at any time next after the beginning of every future Parliament or Representative, and may sit, vote, and act in such then present Parliament with the old Members thereof, by the space of a week, [or some o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther time so to be thought convenient] next before the end or dissolution thereof, &amp; that then such old <hi>Members</hi> (who shall not be again chosen for such new <hi>Members</hi>) may depart and leave the <hi>Members</hi> of the next <hi>Parlament</hi> from such ending or dissolution to be; to sit, vote, and act in such new Parliament so next to be, by themselves. And that [if the Inhabitants of any of such Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Cities, Boroughs, or other places before mentioned, shall have certain knowledge or Intelligence of the death or becoming of inhability or unfitness of any of such Members so by them to be chosen] then they may choose or elect, and send a new Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber for such County, City, or other place, to sit, vote, and act in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ch <gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>l: in the place and stead of such Member so first chosen; and then he shall cease and forbear to act or sit in the same, unless the then present Parliament shall be unwilling to depart with hm.</p>
            <p>And that the Inhabitants of every County, which shall contain in the same ten Hundreds, Tythings, Wapentakes or Lathes, or such like Divisions or more (containing in every one of them ten Parishes or more, and every one of those Parishes one with ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, 50. Housholders, or more, who be, or shall be assessed to pay Taxes to or for the relief of the poor of every of such respe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Parish, may elect or choose only two such Members for fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture Parliaments or Representatives, in manner and form before mentioned. And that every of the Inhabitants of a County, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining lesse, shall so elect or choose only one such Member.</p>
            <p>And that every the Inhabitants of a County containing more, may elect a greater number, according to the proportion or numbers before mentioned,</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:110069:7"/>
            <p>And that the Inhabitants of every City, Borough, Corpora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and other such places, first before mentioned, containing in it half so many of such House-holders, as in such Ten, Hundreds, Lathes, Wapentakes, or such like Divisions, or more, may in like manner elect and choose only one such Member.</p>
            <p>And that the Inhabitants of every one 2. or more of every Ward, of 2. or more Divisions of every greater or more populous City, or other place before mentioned (which shall contain so many of such Inhabitants) may likewise elect or choose only one such Member, and that every such Member may sit, vote, and act as before is mentioned, or that some other numbers concerning the premisses, may be prescribed and enacted by the Parliaments of this Nation, as by their knowledge or certain intelligence they shall find most necessary for the publick benefit.</p>
            <p>And that if the Inhabitants of any County, City, or such other place, shall find themselves grieved, by reason that some other County do or shall elect too many such Members, according to the number of such House-holders, living in the same) that then 2. or 3. discreet, honest, and able in estate of the Inhabitants of e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very County, City, or such other place thereunto next adjoyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and by them in that beh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lf to be chosen, shall and may once in every year at convenient times, take a view or survey, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>telligence of and in every such Parish, and make inquiry to find out or learn what they can concerning the same, and certifie the <hi>Parliaments</hi> of this Nation, the truth and certainty thereof.</p>
            <p>And that the Inhabitants of no Corporation, Borough, or such other place, which be or shall be depopulated, decayed, or ruined in part or in the whole, and shall continue so by the space of 2. or 3. years, (or some other time by the supreme Authority of this Nation so to be thought convenient and shall not by such Authority be accounted a place of great importance, and the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuance of such election or choice by them adjudged to be ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessary to belong to it for the common good) shall hereafter so elect or choose, or intermeddle with any such thing, otherwise then with the Inhabitants of the next adjacent Hundred, W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take, or Lathe, or some other such like Division before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, with whom it may be lawful for them to joyn in such choise or election.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:110069:8"/>
            <p>And that any such chief Constable, Major, or other Officer, may refuse and forbear to receive, or accept of such Note of any other then of such (who of his own knowledge or certain intelligence he knoweth to be capable so to elect or choose, or whose Names shall be shewed to him in such Certificate hereafter mentioned by a known person to such chief Constable, or of one, who shall make it appear by his own Oath, or the Oath of some other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son of credit and repute, that he is so capable.)</p>
            <p>And that any Justice of the Peace, Major, or other such Head-Officer, may be impowered, authorized, and compelled to mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster and take such Oath, being tendred to him in writing, without taking or accepting any thing for the same by himself, or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther. And that any person, who shall depose any thing wilfully fals in that behalf, or concerning any thing therein mentioned, may be subject and liable to, and undergo the pains and penalties in the Statutes, Acts and Lawes provided or enacted against perju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red persons, being convict thereof, as in such cases hath been used and accustomed.</p>
            <p>And that all and every person and persons whatsoever offend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or which shall offend in any thing touching or concerning the premisses, or any thing herein mentioned by them or any of them to be done; shall respectively forfeit and lose and pay 100 l. of lawful <hi>English</hi> money, (or some other some by the said Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority of this Nation to be thought convenient) whereof one moyety thereof to be for the Common-wealth, and the other for him who will sue for the same to be recovered by action of debt, bill, plaint, or information, in which no essoyne, wager of Law, or, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And that those who shall not be taxed for, and do contribute to and for the relief of the poor, shall so elect or choose or intermeddle therewith.</p>
            <p>And that the Collectors for the poor of every such Parish, upon every Request of one or more so to elect, shall certifie their Names of such who do or shall so contribute and request, together with such matters as they shall know or hear (which may disable them from such election) to such chief Constable, Major, or Head-Officer or Officers respectively: And that such Certificate deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered by a known person, shall be taken a sufficient Warrant for them to receive and accept such Note for election of any of such
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:110069:8"/> to be mentioned in such Certificate; unless such chief Constable, Major, or Head-Officer, shall know some apparent matter o-disability of such person or persons in such Certificate, to debar or hinder him, her or them from such election.</p>
            <p>And that any person being a free Denizen of <hi>Engl.</hi> and being taxed, and shall contribute to or for the relief of the poor of the Parish (where he resideth in this Nation) as high, or as much or more then a Free-holder there; or any Lease-Holder or Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py-holder of any Lands who shall have 3. years to come, and the same be of the value of 300 l. or more to be sold, besides the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Rents of the same, and being not disabled from such an e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection or choyce, may elect or choose as aforesaid, as well as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny such Free-holder.</p>
            <p>And that any person (who shall deliver, or cause to be so de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered, any such Note for election to such chief Constable, Major, or other Head-Officer before mentioned respectively) may recall the same in from them again at any time before he or any of them have delivered or shall deliver the same to such Sheriff, and deliver a new one to him or them, who shall (upon request of such person) deliver back such old note to him; so calling for the same, sealed up as at first, and receive and accept such new Note so sealed up, and deliver the same so sealed to such Sheriff, in manner and form before mentioned, or before any such Major, or other Head or chief-Officers before mentioned, have or shall have broken up such Box; and sorted such Notes as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said. And that none of such Sheriffs, Majors, or other such Officers, shall read, view, or see, or permit any other to read, view, or see what names be or shall be in any such Note, till first they be mixt amongst others, and the Letter or Note wherein they were or shall be inclosed, cancelled in such manner, that it may not be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stinguished or known to any, what names were inclosed in any such Letter or Note to be so elected or chosen by any one parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular person.</p>
            <p>And that every such chief Constable shall keep a true Note of the Names and number of the same, of those (who or for whom such Note of Election shal be delivered, and of the delivery of them to such Sheriff) and deliver unto him a true Copy thereof, and he to subscribe the original Note, with his acknowledgement of the receipt thereof under his hand; and that such chief Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stable
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:110069:9"/> shall keep or cause to be kept such original Note for any one therein concerned, to view and see by the space of a year, then next ensuing.</p>
            <p>And that every such Major, or such other of such Head-Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of smaller Cities or Corporations, shall keep such a Note-Book, or Writing of such Notes of election so to be delivered to him or them, to be viewed and seen as aforesaid, by the time a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid.</p>
            <p>And that such <hi>Aldermen, Bayliffs, Burgesses, Masters</hi> of <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies</hi> or <hi>Wards</hi> of the greater <hi>Cities</hi> (who shall take such notes of Election) shall make such Note or Book of the same, in such manner and form as such chief <hi>Constable</hi> is to do, and that such Major or o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>er Head-Officer of such great City shall receive and subscribe such Copy of it in such manner, as such Sheriff is to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive his Copy, and so subscribe the original thereof, and the said inferior Officer so to keep the same, as before mentioned, and for such intent.</p>
            <p>And that no person or persons (against whom any Bill of or concerning the matter of any ind<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ctment or presentment of Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lony, Blasphemy▪ or Seducers thereof, Forgery, Perjury, Suborna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of perjury, Monopolizing, and Cursing, common Drunken<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, Extortion, Disturbance, or Obstructions of the Peace and quiet of this Nation; — or of so many or such other, as by such Authority shall be thought convenient in that behalf, shall be found by any grand Jury or great Inquest to be a true Bill, and personal notice given to him or her thereof, till he or she be acquitted of the same by the petty Jury; or if he or she shall be convicted of any such thing, and have such notice until he or she have or shall have the same reversed, revoked, or overthrown, or annihilated by Writ of Error or Astaint, or motion in Arrest of Judgment, or being convict thereof, until he or she do or shall sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie the same; and as far as he or she be able, the persons thereby damnified or injured, and live soberly, honestly, without any such thing so found, or conviction against him or her, for any of the offences before mentioned, by the space of a year, or some other time so to be thought convenient next after) shall so elect or choose, or be elected or chosen, or so to sit, vote, or act, if e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected or chosen.</p>
            <pb n="13" facs="tcp:110069:9"/>
            <p>And that every one convict of Witch-craft, Murder, wilful Treason, shall for ever stand disabled so to elect or choose, sit, vote or act. And that before the opening of such Box, there may be Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation made by every such Sheriff, or his Deputy or Deputies, in every <hi>Market Town</hi> within his County, &amp; by such <hi>Maj:</hi> or such o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Head-Officer or Officers before mentioned together within the City, Corporation, or other place before mentioned, of which he or they be, or shall be Head-Officers or Officer as aforesaid) of the certain place in manner easie to be found, and the very hour when, or 3. or 4. hours before, when such <hi>Box</hi> is or shall be o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened, (that is to say) every such Sheriff by the space of 4. dayes, and such other Head-Officer by the space of one day next before such day, when such <hi>Box</hi> is to be or shall be opened, and that the place where such <hi>Box</hi> shall be so opened may in a publick open place or Hall, which may well contain 100 men or more, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out too much crowding or thronging, and that so many persons of such persons to be of capacity, there so to choose or elect, or be chosen or elected, may then &amp; there be present if they please <gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o see such things fairly and justly done, or by such Sheriff or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Head-Officer, and his or their Associates before mentioned.</p>
            <p>And that every petty Constable of every Parish of this Nation, shall take a Note of the Names of every one of such respective Parish, who do or shall bring and deliver a Note to him in wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, or aver and affirm that he is capable of such election, and enter the same into a <hi>Book,</hi> and make a <hi>Certificate</hi> thereof to the chief <hi>Constable</hi> of the Hundred, where such Parish shall be, or if in any <hi>City</hi> or <hi>Corporation</hi> of the smaller sort, the Head-Officer or Officers thereof; or if in one of the great Cities to the <hi>Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men</hi> or othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#uom" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> chief Officers of the Ward, or other Division in such great Cities.</p>
            <p>And that every one that shall so deliver such Note, or so aver or affirm, shall write or cause to be written in such Note, or so a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and affirm nothing but truth under the penalties herein men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
            <p>And that every petty <hi>Constable</hi> may reject, so certifying the Name of any such person or persons (if he shall be informed by any person of credit and ability in estate) that he or they, shall not be capable of such choice or election, or shew in parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:110069:10"/> such matter that shall be sufficient so to disable him or them, of or from that capacity.</p>
            <p>And that such person that so shall inform, shall inform nothing but truth, and set the same down in writing under his hand, and deliver the same to the party or parties to be disabled after reason<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able request upon and under the penalty of 50 l. or some other summe to be thought convenient to such party to be paid, and the same to be by him recovered in form and manner herein men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
            <p>And that one capable of such election (who shall doubt of such capacity in any one, whose Name shall be so certified by such Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors and petty Constables) after reasonable Request thereof to him or them, who shall have the custody of any of such Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cates at such times of Request, &amp; a note delivered to him or them of the name of the person or persons so to be doubted of, or shall be permitted to view and see both such Certificates, that by com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring the same together, he may be able to find out and discover the truth of such things.</p>
            <p>And that such Parliament may be adjourned or proroged in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny yeare (only leaving some of the chief of them to sit in the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tervalls, as a general Committee or State) when they have dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>patched all things before them, which can no otherwise be deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined.</p>
            <p>And that if any of such Counties, Cities, Corporations, or other places, shall fail in their new choice or elections, that then in such case, their old Members of Parliament or Representatives may stand and remain for the then next year, to sit, vote, and act as Members or Representers of and in such new <hi>Parliament</hi> or <hi>Representative,</hi> in as large and ample manner and form to all in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents and purposes, as if they had been chosen or elected again for Members or Representers in or of such Parliament or Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sentative.</p>
            <p>And that before any new Act or Statute hereafter be or shall be made or enacted, or any old Law, Statute, or Ordinance re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pealed, other then such, for which many people of the greatest part of the Counties, Cities, Boroughs, Towns Corporate, Cinque-Ports of this Nation, and other places before mentioned; which be or shall be incorporated with the same (who have or
<pb facs="tcp:110069:10"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:110069:11"/>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:110069:11"/> shall have power or Authority for such Choyce or Election) shall Petition to future Parliaments or Representatives, and publish to common view in print, and no Answer or Objections written and published against the same in print, by the consent of the like num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of people of such part of such Cities, Counties, or other the places before mentioned, within ten days, or some other time (so to be thought convenient) next after such Petitions published, without the knowledg of or notice given to all the Members of such Parliament, (who shall be within two miles of the sitting of the same, and leave notice with some Officer of such Parliament, in what place or places the dwellings or lodgings be or shall be, and the same be there easie to be found,) or left for every of them at such his dwelling or lodging, with some by him there appointed to receive the same, if he do or shall appoint any so to do, within twelve hours next before such acting, altering or repealing.</p>
            <q>A short view of the Queries and Proposals formerly published, and of the Heads of others, (in short time hereafter to be pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lished at large, for the perfect understanding of the common People,) whereby those, who have had the experience of the matter in the same, may easily gather how the Millions of Money before mentioned may be yearly saved to the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of this Nation, which formerly have unlawfully been exacted from them every year.</q>
            <p n="1">1. By the Queries concerning Bills, Plaints and Informations, and Pleas and Answers, Replications and Rejoynders, and Rebut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters and Surrebutters, and such like (if the same were enacted) would be yearly saved to the People of this Nation, Two hundred and forty thousand pounds.</p>
            <p n="2">2. And (if the same were done of the Queries concerning the multitudes of unnecessary Orders, delays, charges and trouble in Courts, called English Courts, or Courts of Equity, with an additi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>onal Quere written at the first, but forborn to be published with the others at the request of some Gentlemen) there would thereby be yearly so saved, Seven hundred and twenty thousand pounds.</p>
            <p n="3">
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:110069:12"/>3. And (if the <hi>Proposals</hi> for the more speedy satisfaction of Creditors with little Charge or Trouble, of, and against such as be of Ability, and lie in Prison, and conceal their Estates, and setting at large Prisoners for debt and damages, not able to pay or satisfie the same were enacted) thereby then would be yearly so saved Three hundred thousand pounds (which is esteemed by some to be so much more) besides losses to Creditors to as much.</p>
            <p n="4">4. And by the <hi>Proposals</hi> for Prevention of the great Trouble and Charge which the People of this Nation have been put to by wrongful Arrests and Imprisonments, and for taking away the trouble and charge which divers have been at to procure Arrests and Appearances (if the like were so done) yearly would be so saved Three hundred and seventy thousand pounds, besides losses prevented to as much.</p>
            <p n="5">5. And if the same were done with the <hi>Proposals</hi> concerning the Principal Courts of <hi>England,</hi> and concerning the keeping of the Terms, as anciently they have been, thereby yearly would be saved for the same benefit Four hundred and ninety thousand pounds.</p>
            <p n="6">6. And by the <hi>Propositions</hi> for the Recording of Deeds and Conveyances, Judgments, Statutes and Recognizances, &amp;c. (if the same, and the second part thereof, written, and ready to be publish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, were enacted,) there would be so saved, and divers people of this Nation preserved from being defrauded of a Million of Money yearly hereafter.</p>
            <p n="7">7. And by these present <hi>Propositions</hi> (if the like were done with the same) would thereby be saved for the same benefit and advantage, One hundred thousand pounds every year, when Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liaments be chosen.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Additional Quere</hi> to the second is intended, as conveniency happen, to be published with the second part of the sixth, with o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther things concerning Errors, and Arrest of Judgments, Amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of Mistakes, to prevent Non-suits, prevention of Fraud, in serving Executions, and dangers of Officers executing the same,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:110069:12"/> retorning impartial Jurors, with divers other things, in order to the saving much more money yearly to the people of this Nation.</p>
            <p>The first and second were printed in the year 1647. by <hi>Francis Leach.</hi> And the third in the year 1650. by <hi>John Macock.</hi> And the fourth in the same year by the said <hi>Francis Leach;</hi> and are all three to be sold by <hi>Lawrence Blaiklock</hi> by Temple Bar.</p>
            <p>The fifth and sixth were printed by <hi>Francis Leach,</hi> and are to be sold by <hi>George Badger</hi> in S. <hi>Dunstans</hi> Church yard.</p>
            <p>And this present is to be sold by <hi>William Lee, Lawrence Blaiklock,</hi> and <hi>Gabriel Bedell</hi> in Fleet-street; <hi>Lawrence Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> near the Savoy, and <hi>Lodowick Lloyd</hi> in Popes head-Alley.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>By <hi>William Leach</hi> of the middle Temple, Gent.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>The End.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>